How
如何
to make friends with the ex-wife?
与前妻成为朋友
Let me answer your question.
如何跟前妻成为朋友呢
In general,
一般来说
it's scarcely possible for a man
一个男人
to maintain friendship
跟前妻成为朋友
with your ex-wife.
几乎是不可能的事情
But if you
但是如果你们离了婚
still hope
还是想继续
to be friends after the divorce,
成为朋友的话呢
you may
也不是完全没有可能的
still get a chance.
还是有机会的
That's good.
那就好
So, first of all,
那首先呢
it had to be a peaceful separation
就是你们在离婚的时候
for your divorce.
必须是和平分手
You didn't kick up a row.
没有大吵大闹
Absolutely not.
绝对没有
So if both sides
那如果他们
keep on good terms with each other,
彼此不排斥对方的话
it means they're broad-minded
那说明他们的格局
and generous.
是非常之大的
Wanzhen is good in this respect.
婉真的格局还是可以的
Above all,
最重要的是
if the ex-wife
如果前妻
or the ex-husband
没有寻找新的另一半
doesn't look for
或者前夫没有寻找
a new partner,
新的另一春的话
your marital relations
这种婚姻关系
may be maintained.
就不会被打破
I'll never find another woman.
我是绝对不会再一春的
Wanzhen probably won't do it either.
婉真应该也不会
How to remarry the ex-wife?
如何与前妻复婚
Actually eighty-five percent
其实百分之八十五的
of divorce
婚姻啊
can be restored.
都是可以挽回的
First of all,
首先
you listen to what she says.
去倾听对方的声音
Show her your sincerity.
主动表达你的诚意
I said it all.
我这都表达了
No use, man.
没用 哥们儿
Use the resources of marriage.
利用婚姻的资源
For example,
比如
create some
去制造一些
warm and beautiful moments
父母和孩子在一起
between parents and children.
温馨美好的画面
Use resources.
利用资源
Since
可既然
you two
你们的婚姻已经走到了
are divorced,
离婚的境地
it means
那就说明
some characters of you
你的身上
made her
一定有一些令她
weary.
十分厌烦的东西
If you wish to get remarried with her,
所以想要复婚
you've to figure out
你就必须去思考
what these flaws are.
自身的缺陷究竟是什么
Then
随后呀
you strive to meet what your ex-wife
向着前妻的核心需求
really needs.
去努力拼搏
Only if you do that,
复婚
can your marriage be restored.
才有可能
What she really needs.
核心需求
Resources.
资源
Hello.
喂
Zhou Yao.
周耀
It's me, Chan Wanzhen.
是我 陈婉真
Oh, Wendy.
温蒂啊
What's up?
怎么想起给我打电话了
Wanna catch up?
要叙叙旧啊
I'm calling you
我给你打这个电话呢
as I think
是因为我觉得
you're the best player
你是金融行业
in financial field.
最优秀的人
So,
所以呢
I have a question for you.
有个问题想请教一下你
Okay, what is it?
好 什么问题
I've been investigating
我最近在调查
the financial status of a company.
一家公司的财务状况
So through various channels
那在各个渠道呢
some financial data has been collected.
收集到了一些财务数据
What's your discovery?
你发现了什么
This group runs their main business
这家公司呢
in the secondary industry,
主业是第二产业
It's a pillar type.
就支柱型的那一种
Moreover,
而且呢
it's a big company.
公司规模非常大
To the outsiders,
对外呢
they're very successful.
是很风光
But I found
但是我发现
their debt ratio
他们的财务
was very high.
负债率非常高
It's already higher
已经超过了
than the warning level of the bank.
银行的警戒线
if I'm
如果
right,
我没有分析错的话
they're gonna go bankrupt soon.
近期会要爆雷
A huge business empire
一个超大型的商业帝国
is about to crash.
马上就要崩盘了
I know
我知道你查的
which company it is.
是哪家公司
I've been keeping eyes on it, too.
我也一直在关注它
If any of your friends
如果你的朋友
owns its stocks
持有它的股票
and financial products,
和金融产品
please advise them to sell off at once.
建议赶紧抛
Your judgment is very accurate.
你的判断非常准确
The company is gonna collapse.
大厦将倾
I'm an
连我一个从业执照
unlicensed practitioner,
都没有的人
yet you're so confident in me.
你这么肯定
Thank you, Zhou Yao.
谢谢你啊 周耀
Wendy.
温蒂
You know
你知道你身上
the most powerful capability of you
最厉害的是什么吗
is the intuition.
就是直觉
You intuition judgment is awesome.
你的直觉非常地准
Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真
I sincerely invite you
我郑重地向你发出邀请
to join
我 和我的耀辉投资
Yaohui Investments.
等你来
Got it.
我知道啦
Come on, give it to me.
来来来 给我 给我
Don't
以后啊
use lipsticks any more.
这口红不能用了
It makes me look good.
涂点口红气色好
Rest assured.
你放心
Just use the formula I gave you on time,
你只要按时用我的方子
I promise you will look good.
我保证你气色好
When you weren't at home yesterday,
昨天你不在家的时候
I cleaned up the room.
我打扫卫生
I checked
我把这些化妆品
all these makeups,
都扫了一遍
including this lipstick.
包括这个口红
Most of them are in inferior quality.
基本上都不合格
They contain lead and mercury.
含铅和汞
Mercury, you know?
汞你知道吗
It's
就是水银
poisonous.
有毒
Then what?
然后呢
You can't use it.
然后你就不能用啦
Only this one
只有这个
can be used
我看了
as I checked.
这个能用
I picked it out for you
我给你挑出来了
and put it here.
放到这儿
This is made from plants.
这个是纯天然植物的
You can use it.
你以后就用这个
I'm putting them away, okay?
那我就给你收了啊
Are you gonna throw them away?
那是都扔了吗
No.
不扔
I will keep them for you.
我先给你保管着
After you deliver the baby,
等你生完孩子
I gonna give them back to you, okay?
再给你用好吗
Okay.
好
Come on.
来来来 快
You sit over here.
你先坐这边
Let me check.
看看啊
Unhealthy.
不安全
It'll be put away.
这个收了
Below standard.
不合格
Pack them in.
收了
What are you doing, Jing?
干什么呢 姐
And this one.
这个
The induction cooker
以后啊
and pot
这电磁锅电磁炉
can't be used.
都不能用了
They're radiative.
有辐射
Not this one.
这个不行
We need it to steam buns
这得蒸馒头
and rice.
它蒸米饭呢
No!
蒸什么馒头
We can use gas.
有明火啊
Enough.
行了 行了
Leave me alone. I can handle it.
你不用操心 有我呢
Hang on.
等一下
Just a moment.
来了
Oh...
这这这
What the hell is going on here?
搞什么鬼这
Give this to Meng'an.
把这个给梦安
What's this?
这什么
Listen.
我跟你说
I bought her
我给她买的
radiation protective clothes for pregnant women.
孕妇防辐射罩衣
A lot of computers
她到了办公室以后
are in her offices.
不是有很多电脑吗
She can put it on
她把这个一穿
for radiation protection.
防辐射
What's the use?
这有什么用
She won't wear it.
她不会穿的
The radiation
这个平时生活里的
of the articles
那些辐射
for daily use
对人体的伤害
is almost unharmful.
是微乎其微的
Don't listen to the false ad.
你不要听那些虚假宣传
It's useless.
没用的
But they sell it.
没用人家还能卖
We'd rather
咱宁愿信其有
believe the ad.
不能信其无
Besides,
再说了
Those radiation
平常那个辐射
unharmful to us
对我们正常人可以
is still unsafe to pregnant women.
对孕妇就是不行的
You know?
你知道吗
No more talking.
你别说这么多了
Just give it to her.
你给她就行了
She won't wear it.
她不会穿的
How can you be
你怎么就知道
so sure?
她不会穿哪
I'm her husband.
我是她老公
Of course, I know.
我怎么会不知道
You let her make the decision.
你不要替她做决定
Enough.
行 行了 行了
Don't keep your wife waiting.
别让你老婆等急了
Hurry, hurry.
快快快
Just take it and give it to her
拿着给她就行了
Go, go.
走走走
Don't keep her waiting.
别让你媳妇等急了
That's it.
行了行了
It's...
这
It's too hard to convince him.
做点工作太难了
Oh...
这这这
He knows nothing about scientific knowledge.
一点都没有科学知识
Geez.
天哪
Okay.
穿
I'll wear it!
我穿
No!
穿什么穿
If you get the knowledge, you won't wear it.
明摆的就是智商税嘛
It's not about knowledge,
这跟智商没关系
but a worldly wisdom.
这是情商的问题
What do you mean?
说谁呢
See?
你看
You've got to have the wisdom.
可不就是吗
You know she is stubborn,
大姐什么脾气
right?
你还不知道吗
Even if I'm not wearing it today,
我今天不穿
she's gonna put it on for me
她明天也得给我摁那儿
tomorrow.
让我穿上
I might as well just tell her
我还不如就告诉她
I wore it.
我穿了
Then I can put it in the car.
然后就把它放在车里边
She won't know
她哪儿知道
whether I wore it or not.
我在公司里穿没穿呢
Right?
对吧
She came out.
她出来了
Hurry.
快快快
Let's go.
赶紧走 赶紧走
No!
走什么呀
Put it on.
穿
I put it on and show her,
穿上给她看一眼
then she'll let it go, you know?
这事就了了 你知道吗
Jing.
大姐
You've put it on?
穿上了
How do you like it?
怎么样 喜欢吗
I love it.
特别喜欢
I was trying
我头两天还想说
to buy one on line
下单买一件
a few days ago.
这个防护服呢
Great.
你看 你看
Li Lin,
李临
I told you.
我就说嘛
Let her make the decision.
你不要替梦安做主
We'll be late.
快迟到了
Jing, we gotta go.
姐 我们 我们得走了
Wait.
等一下
Get off.
下来
My dear sister,
我亲爱的姐姐
we're gonna be late.
我们要迟到了
Get off!
下来
Why?
下来干什么
Get off.
下去 下去
Come.
来
Tell me.
说
What's wrong now?
又怎么了
She's pregnant,
她一个孕妇
isn't it?
是吧
She needs to be highly concentrated for driving.
这个开车会高度集中的
She's to brake frequently.
刹车 刹车 刹车
It's dangerous and may cause miscarriage.
流产怎么办
I'll drive.
我开
Right?
是不这意思
Bingo.
对
Sorry for my inconsideration.
对不起 疏忽了
You were indeed inconsiderate.
你确实疏忽了
Come.
走
You just sit in the car.
你坐车就好了
Don't drive.
不要开车
Okay?
好吧
Don't drive during your pregnancy.
以后你不要开车
Come.
来
Watch out.
慢一点啊
Okay.
好
Here, fasten the seat belt.
来 安全带
Close the car door.
关门了
Drive carefully.
你给我慢点
Just close it!
关门啊
Be careful.
慢一点啊
Move aside. I'm turning off.
躲开 我这个拐弯呢我
Yeah.
对啊
You're almost like He now.
你现在跟小荷差不多啦
Where did you wash your face?
脸在哪儿洗的
At home.
在家
My husband's sister
我大姑姐
took all
把我所有的化妆品
my makeups away. I've got no choice.
全都没收了 没办法
The spare ones come in handy.
备用装上场了
What's this?
这是 这什么东西啊
An apron?
围裙
Why do you take this?
戴围裙干吗
Radiation protective clothes for pregnant women.
孕妇防护服
You haven't seen it, I guess.
没见过吧
Wow, look.
什么情况
You just declared your pregnancy yesterday.
昨天刚官宣怀孕
Now you're wearing it.
今天全面进入角色啦
You're showing everyone that
这相当于写了四个字啊
you're pregnant.
我是孕妇
My husband's sister bought it for me.
大姑姐给买的
Does it work?
这玩意儿管用吗
Yeah.
管用啊
If I need to take the subway
等哪天
when my license plate number
车限行了
is in the traffic restriction,
我坐地铁
I'll wear it.
就穿上它
Someone will surely offer a seat to me.
保准有人给我让大座
Good idea.
这招好
I'll buy one later on.
回头我也搞一件
Right?
是吧
I've found
我发现这人生啊
something is inevitable in life.
就是守恒的
When I was getting married,
要结婚那会儿啊
I was quite happy for a period
因为没有婆婆
as I wouldn't have a mother-in-law.
暗戳戳地高兴了很久
Unexpectedly,
结果呢
my husband's sister
给我弄来了这样的
comes.
一个大姑姐
She is even harder to get along than a mother-in-law.
比婆婆还婆婆
Am I right?
你说
Something in life
人生这课
is inevitable, right?
是不一门也少不了
Exactly.
绝对少不了
Make vigorous efforts
精进
for big achievements.
跃迁
Let's go!
走
I heard
我听说
Ms. Xu wanted to promote me.
许总监想要提拔我
Is it true?
是真的还是假的呀
Yes, I heard of it.
确实是有这个风声
Meichuan,
所以美川
you've to know how to do well.
你要懂得做啊
Okay.
好嘞
Go ahead.
忙吧 忙吧
What do you want for lunch?
这中午吃点啥呀
Ms. Xu!
许总监
Let me help you.
我扶你 我扶你
Come on.
来来来
No, well.
不 这
Slow down.
慢点 慢点
Take care of the baby.
别动了胎气
Make way.
让一让 让一让
Make way, everyone.
都让一让
Knock it off.
别闹了
Nobody is here.
哪儿有人啊
It's a rehearsal.
演练 演练一下
Go, go.
走走走
No.
不
In advanced maternal age,
年纪大了 我跟你说
you've to be careful.
这真的要注意 是不是
Meichuan,
美川
hold Ms. Xu.
扶一下呀
You're making a fuss.
不用
Ms. Xu,
总监
I have some projects
刚好那个我手底下
to report
有几个项目
to you.
想跟您汇报一下
Let's go to my office.
去我办公室吧
Okay.
好
Ms. Xu.
许总监早
Just go ahead with your work, okay?
咱都跟往常一样好不好
Sit down.
来 坐坐坐
These are all baby's stuff
这些都是我送的
I bought.
都是些小孩用的东西
Oh, that's too kind of you.
这 太客气了吧
After all, it's good news.
毕竟是喜事嘛
Mr. Zhang told me
张总跟我说了
to learn from you
让我跟您好好学习
and do a good job.
好好干
So that the content department
让咱们内容部啊
can transit and operate well
平稳地度过孕期
during your pregnancy and maternity leave.
还有产假
The transition period has to be copped with.
先不说过渡期这个事
But first of all, I wish you
我倒是希望你
to get familiar with the business soon.
能够尽快地熟悉业务
Then you can take that responsibility.
把这份责任承担起来
I hope you'll take over my job.
等你当我接班人啊
Thank you Ms. Xu. I'll work hard.
谢谢许总监 我努力
Have a seat.
坐吧
Sugar-free?
无糖的
On discount.
打折
Four pieces are enough.
四个就够啦
She's to eat them every day.
每天都要吃
They're on discount.
打折
You don't have to follow me.
你不用陪我了
I can buy things myself.
我自己可以
I'll be with you.
我陪会儿你
What's up?
怎么了
Lost your job?
失业啦
No, I didn't.
谁 谁失业了
I work at a university now.
我现在在高校上班
I've time before going to work.
这时间上我比较好掌控
I'll be here with you.
我陪会儿你
I know
我知道
you're just worried about me buying things
你就是怕我乱花钱
recklessly.
乱买东西
Right.
对了
I don't want you to spend money recklessly.
我就是怕你乱花钱
You're right.
说对了
Don't worry.
放心吧
I'm more experienced in shopping than you.
我比你老道啊
I know what to buy.
会买东西
Take some of these.
拿点这个吧
Get the hawthorn, not others.
来拿点山楂 别拿别的
Hawthorn is good.
山楂好
Meng'an has a bad appetite lately.
梦安最近 胃口不好
Get her hawthorns to whet her appetite.
我给她买点山楂开开胃
It contains too much sugar.
糖分太高了
She can't eat this.
这个不能吃
What can she eat?
那什么能吃
Spare ribs.
排骨
I'll get some
一会儿我去买排骨
to stew tonight.
咱们晚上炖排骨
Okay. Yunjie also likes to eat.
行 云阶也爱吃排骨
Don't care too much
现在我们
about Yunjie.
就不要操心云阶了
Just
我们就只想
take good care of Meng'an.
把梦安照顾好就行了
That's not reasonable.
那你这话说的
Yunge is fifteen years old.
云阶现在 十五岁
It's her growth period.
正是生长发育期
Better for her to eat some nutritious food.
怎么能没有营养呢
Alright.
好好好
Jing,
姐
you can stay here.
我跟你说你来归来
But
但是呢
make no trouble for me.
你不要给我惹事
What trouble have I gotten you into?
我给你惹什么事了
You came here,
你这一来
then Mengxin's wound
人梦心那伤口
tore apart.
裂了
What's going on?
怎么回事
Not my fault.
那个能怪我吗
She has a bad temper.
她自己脾气太大
Really?
是吗
Yeah.
对啊
How long are you gonna stay here?
你 来几天啊 这次
You've seen her
你差不多
and felt relieved.
看得你也放心了
Then
就
you can go back.
回去吧
These white fungi are good.
这银耳真不错
I can make white fungi soup with pears.
银耳雪梨汤
You think I have nothing to do?
你以为我闲得没事啊
Meng'an is
我不是就看着
pregnant,
梦安怀孕了吗
I just wanna help.
我就想来帮帮忙
It's also
也是为了我们
for the descendant of the Li family.
李家的后代
I know you mean well.
我知道你是好心
500 grams, please.
来一斤
But
但是吧
as the saying goes,
俗话说得好
harmony at home brings prosperity.
家和万事兴
The key word is harmony.
关键是在这个和字上
It means we've to know
就是每个人啊
our place in life
一定要知道自己的位置
and say proper words.
说该说的话
You're
你
my sister.
是大姑姐
Not a mother-in-law.
不是婆婆
Did I say I was the mother-in-law?
我说我是婆婆了吗
I get along with Meng'an.
我跟梦安都挺好的
Don't I?
是吧
You've been talking nonsense.
你这一天叽叽歪歪的
How annoying!
你烦不烦呀
What are you doing?
你干吗
Put it inside.
你给我放那儿
Lower your voice.
小声点
The smell of cinnamon is too strong.
桂皮的味太大了
Meng'an is pregnant.
现在梦安她怀着孕呢
She can't stand this.
这种受不了
I need it for cooking.
我做饭要用的
Put it here.
你给我放这儿
She doesn't want this.
她不要这个
I know her well.
我了解她
Take it back.
你给我拿回来
No.
我不拿
I decide what I'll buy.
买什么我做主
You hear me?
我买什么我做主
It's on me.
我买单
Too bad.
完了
Ms. Xu,
许总监
I got you cubilose drink.
我给你买了燕窝饮品
Remember to drink it later.
一会儿记得喝
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You're welcome.
应该的
Ms. Xu,
许总监
will we still hold the meeting this afternoon?
咱下午的会 还开吗
Yeah. Why not?
开啊 为什么不开了
We are worried that you'll be too tired.
大家伙怕你太累了
Maybe we can do it tomorrow.
要不咱明天开吧
No, go ahead as scheduled.
不不不 正常 下午开
Tell them
跟大家伙说一声
I'm fine with it.
我没事
Okay.
好
Ms. Xu, you are here.
许总监 你在这儿啊
I've been looking for you.
找你半天呢
Oh my.
我去
They are all bought
这
by other colleagues?
这全是大伙给你买的
Yeah.
是啊
Well,
不是
I also bought you a lot.
我还给你买一大堆呢
Can you eat them up?
你吃得完吗这
Definitely not.
肯定吃不完
Do you want to eat some for me?
要不你帮我消化点
No.
我怎么帮你
But these things
但这些东西
are high in oil and sugar.
全都是高油高糖啊
You'd better not eat too much.
你得少吃
You're experienced in this.
一看您就是过来人
My wife,
我那媳妇
about the same age of you,
跟你差不多年纪
has just conceived a second child.
也刚有二胎
When did she get pregnant?
什么时候的事啊
How many months of it?
几个月啦
Just three months.
刚刚三个月
It's indeed almost the same time.
那还真差不多
But I think
但我觉得
you and your husband
你跟你家那口子
are brave.
挺敢的
To be honest,
真的
it took me and my wife
我跟我媳妇
a careful consideration
那是纠结了多久
before we made our mind to have a second child.
才决定要老二的
Are you kidding?
您不至于吧
You're a vice president.
您都副总了
To raise one more child
多养一个孩子
wouldn't be a financial burden to you.
应该还好吧
It's not what you think.
真不是你想的那样
Let me tell you.
我跟你说
A child already
这有一个孩子
makes us stressed out.
压力已经很大了
If a second one comes,
这要再有第二个
I really need to get another job
那真得再打一份工
for raising the child.
赚奶粉钱了
You didn't really drink
那天那酒
on the business luncheon, did you?
没真喝吧
Yes, I did.
肯定真喝呀
Are you serious?
真 真喝了
You're pregnant,
你都怀孕了
yet you still drank it?
你还敢喝酒啊
Well, it's for business, right?
那这不是去跑业务吗
It's okay. If I drink too much,
没事 喝多了都扶墙
I can just go home to throw it up.
回家吐就行
You work so hard.
真拼哪
It's been hard on you.
不容易 不容易
But take care of your health.
但还是要注意身体啊
Eat in moderation.
少吃 适量啊
I'm leaving.
走了
Work so hard.
太拼了
So nice.
真好
Someone is awaiting me.
这出差回来 有人等
Wonderful.
有人等啊
A long time since last time.
好久没有这样的待遇了
I wanna talk with you about something important.
我找你有正事
Your business
你的事
is definitely important to me.
对于我来说都是正事
Some of your friends
你的几个朋友
registered
在我公司呢
in my company.
登记过
But I can't reach them.
但是我联系不上他们
Can you put me in touch with them?
你能帮我联系一下吗
I need to talk to them.
我找他们有事
Were they not answering your calls?
不接你电话啊
Which one, you mean?
谁啊
Why didn't he answer?
为什么不接你电话啊
He could be your friend
那可能是你的朋友呗
on your side.
站你那头
No, no.
别别别 别
I've not said a single bad word
我可没在任何人那儿
about you before anyone.
说过你半个不字
I know.
我知道
Maybe I'm salesperson now.
那可能我现在是销售
It's reasonable for them to block me.
那屏蔽我也正常啊
So, you see.
所以呀 你说
Why do you have to
干吗非干这工作
do sales?
挣这份钱呀
Don't worry. It won't last long.
放心吧 干不了多久了
I won't bother you anymore.
以后再也不会麻烦你了
You've quit?
不干啦
Then, what...
不 那
What are your planning to do?
以后你怎么打算啊
Do I have to report it to you?
有必要向你汇报吗
I'm sending you the name list.
我把名单发你
Oh, Mr. Wu wasn't answering your calls, too.
老吴也不接你电话啊
Mr. Wu, this is Yu Hai.
老吴 我于海
My...
那个 我们家
My kid's mom
那个 孩子她妈呀
is a salesperson.
现在不是做销售了吗
So, she needs to talk to you.
那个她有事跟你联系啊
Don't hang up.
不许挂我电话啊
She's right next to me.
她就在我旁边呢
She'll talk to you.
我让她跟你说啊
Just listen to what she says.
你老实听着啊
Hello, Mr. Wu.
喂 吴总
Hello.
您好 您好
This is Chen Wanzhen.
我是陈婉真啊
Did our salesperson
对 我们销售
call you?
给你打电话了吧
Yeah. Don't buy a financial product.
不要买理财 对
You'd better think about it carefully.
你要慎重考虑啊
It's a risk.
这是有风险的
Is it over?
打完了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
I'm leaving.
那我 走了
No, no.
别别别 你看你
You've already here.
来都来了
How about
要不咱们到
going to the Chinese restaurant over there
那边那个中餐厅
to have a meal?
吃个饭吧
No, I already had.
不了 我吃过了
So,
那
go to my room for a while.
回我房间里坐一会儿
What do you want?
你想什么呢
No, no.
不是 不是 不
You're overthinking.
我不是那个意思
I brought presents for our child.
我给孩子啊 带礼物了
It's in the suitcase.
在箱子里呢
It's not good
你说这在大堂里打开吧
to open it in the lobby.
那不好看 是吧
Smelly shoes
里边又臭鞋
and socks are in it.
又烂袜子的
The toy
这玩具
is packed with these things?
跟臭鞋烂袜子放一起
I don't want it.
我不要了
No, no.
没有 没没没
No.
没有 没有
It's wrapped
我拿那个保鲜袋
by the ziploc bag.
我都给它保鲜
They're
不是 封起来了
separated.
隔着呢
Let's go.
走走走 走
Just a moment.
就这一下
I'll bring it out for you.
我就给你拿出来
You can take it and leave.
你拿着就可以走 好吧
You still don't live at home.
你现在还是不回家住啊
It's no fun going home.
回家也没意思
None of you are there.
你们都不在
So it's deserted.
房子空空落落的
Such a big house.
那么大房子
It's a pity.
空在那儿可惜了
You might as well rent it out.
你还不如租出去呢
You can earn some money.
还有一笔租金
Why would I rent it?
我租它干吗呀
I won't let someone else sleep in my bed
我让别人睡我的床
and use
让别人
our kitchen and utensils,
用咱们的厨房餐具
and our toilet.
用咱马桶啊
That's our home.
那是咱的家
Our former home.
曾经的家
Actually,
其实啊
you know,
这
only a place with families
家人在哪儿
can be called home.
哪儿就是家
Alright, I've got the present.
行了 这礼物也拿着了
I'm leaving.
我走啦
Wait.
你等等
Wait a minute.
你等一下啊
I have a meeting
那个我下午啊
with an investor this afternoon.
我要去见一个投资人
I wanna
我呢
wear this suit,
想穿这西装
and
然后
the shirt.
这衬衫
You...
你你你
pick a tie for me, okay?
你帮我搭一条领带呗
Please.
搭一下呗
The blue one.
蓝色的吧
This one?
这个啊
Perfect.
靠谱
Look.
那以后这样吧
If I have a meeting with someone
我出门要办事啊
and don't know which clothes to wear,
穿哪身衣服
I'll take pictures for you
我都给你拍了照片
to help me choose from?
你帮我选选呗
No need, Yu Hai.
没必要 于海
If you have nothing to say,
你要实在没话的话
you don't have to find a topic to talk.
真的不用特意找话题
It's so hard
你不觉得
for you
你之所以
to find a topic
这么费劲地找话题
to talk with me.
跟我说
Isn't it
就是因为我们之间
because we have nothing in common?
真的没有共同语言吗
It proves
从这个角度看
it's a wise decision for us to get divorced.
我们分开 还是明智的
No.
不是 别
Why do you
你这
have to say like that?
你别别 别这么说啊
I used to help you match your clothes
以前我帮你搭配衣服
as I was your wife.
那因为我是于太太
It was what a wife would do.
是我份内的事
But now I think
但现在我看来这件事情
what matters is not what you wear.
不重要
What the investors
这投资人啊
hope to see is your strength.
最想看到的是你的实力
Even if you wear a hoodie
哪怕你穿着帽衫
and sweatpants,
运动裤
they'll still choose to be your partner
只要蓝海有投资的价值
as long as Blue Ocean is worth investing in.
其他的都无所谓
What do you say?
你说呢
You're right.
你说得对
So,
所以
don't get yourself distracted.
你现在其他都不要想
Just focus on your career.
你就心无旁骛地干事业
That's what the investor
这才是投资人
wish to see,
最想看到的
a diligent boss of a startup.
创业公司老板
Wish you success!
祝你成功
So
所以呢
being pregnant with a second child
怀二胎
is a good thing.
确实是件好事
It can get me
可以让我在公司的
more attention
关注度
in the company.
直线上升
And I have a sense
且存在感
of presence.
爆棚
Are you done?
说完了
It's overtime.
超时了
It only takes two or three minutes
你每次自洽
for you to be self-consistent.
只需要两到三分钟
But It took you five minutes and 36 seconds today.
今天五分三十六秒
The point is it doesn't work out so well.
关键是效果不太理想啊
What do you think I can do
你说能有什么办法
to get everyone
让大家对我的关注度
have less attention on me?
降一降呢
It's unlikely to lessen it.
降不大可能
But we can divert their attention to others.
但可以一起抬高
How?
怎么抬高
Mass pregnancy,
集体怀孕
including all.
不分男女
Mr. Zhou
那人家小周总
is gonna have a second baby.
也要二胎了呀
Why doesn't everyone
为什么他的关注度
pay more attention to him?
就没有变化呢
What trick did he use?
你说他用了什么招
Analyze the reason for me.
你帮我分析分析
Due to gender difference.
性别
I'm frustrated to hear this.
扎心了啊
No need to be frustrated.
也没必要沮丧
Having a second child
二胎嘛 长远上来看
is indeed a happy event in the long run.
它确实是个喜事
But just for this period,
但就这段时间
it will indeed
它确实会对
impact a working woman's career.
职业女性造成影响
But I think six months
不过我认为六个月嘛
is just
它只是人生道路上的
like a pit in your life.
一个小坑
You can exert your strength to jump it over.
那使使劲就跳过去了
So I'd like to say
要不那么喜欢
it's great to talk to you.
跟你聊天呢
You're far-sighted.
有格局
Look,
你说
you're ten years younger than me.
你比我小十几岁呢
How can you
怎么就能把这些问题
see these things through?
都看得那么透彻呢
The onlookers see most clearly.
旁观者清啊
It's just normal
你这段期间
if you can't see the problems
如果能像我看得
through like me
这么明白
as you're pregnant.
也不对
That really comforts me.
这句话确实安慰到我了
So tell me
那你说
what I should do next.
我接下来该怎么办呢
The due date is more than six months away.
距离预产期还有半年多
You can
用这段时间
arrange all the work during this time.
做好所有的工作布局
Use the power of a team
用团队的力量
to get through
来稳定地度过
this special time.
这段特殊的时期
That's what I'm planning.
我也是这么计划的
However,
但是
you've to deal with Mr. Zhang.
张总是个问题
Have you thought about it?
你有考虑过
How do you prove to him
怎么向老板证明
that you can still
你怀孕的这段时间
lead the team
仍然能带着团队
to meet targets during your pregnancy?
完成指标和任务吗
You've to
你还是得给他
make him feel assured.
吃个定心丸的
I see.
明白
Your files.
您的文件
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm at the sales office.
我在售楼处
The real estate company
就是我们买房的
where we bought our apartments.
那个地产公司
They've launched wealth management products.
他们家推出理财产品
The interest rates are high.
利率挺不错的
Come and have a look.
你过来看看
Okay.
好
Hello, sir.
叔叔你好
Hello.
你好
Are you here to buy financial products?
您是来买理财产品吗
Yeah.
是啊
I'm a regular customer
我 我们是这家公司的
of this company.
老业主了
My two apartments
我们家两套房子
were bought from them.
都是在这儿买的
Buying an apartment is okay.
买房没问题
But you've to be prudent
但是理财产品
about the wealth management product.
你要谨慎啊
Why?
为什么啊
You're...?
你是
I'm a salesperson of this company.
我是这公司的销售
Feifei's call.
菲菲的
So,
我说姑娘
you do sales.
你是搞销售的
But you talk to me not to buy it.
不让我买
What do you mean?
这是什么意思啊
If I buy it
是不是因为我们买了
and take a share,
占了份额
then you can't
你就不能
leave it for your family, right?
给你们家里人留了
Sir, you take me wrong.
叔叔 您误会我了
I'm trying to help you.
我是替您着想
Ms.,
我说姑娘
you seem kind to me.
我看你挺善良的
What?
不
But you even deceive the elderly.
连老人都欺骗呀
Sir, I'm trying to help you.
叔叔 我是替你着想
No, no. I'm not talking to you.
不不不 不跟你谈
Stop. Stop talking.
得得 不谈
That's what
线上投放的基本情况
about the online sales arrangement.
就是这样
Anything else?
还有什么补充吗
No.
没有
Mr. Zhang, we...
那张总
The meeting is over then.
没了就散会呗
It's over.
散吧
Do you have any other instructions?
您是还有什么指示吗
It's your department's internal meeting.
你们部门的内部会议
Why do you ask me to sit in?
你干吗让我过来旁听啊
After the content division merger,
这不是
it's
内容部合并之后
the first quarterly outlook.
第一次做季度展望吗
And the team building
而且团队搭建
is done.
现在也完成了
I'm supposed to report it to you.
不得跟您汇报一下啊
Not to make me feel assured?
不是为了让我宽心哪
It's not
不是那个瑞秋
Rachel's stupid idea
那个狗头军师
for you?
给你出的主意啊
You found it.
看出来了
Of course.
那是
I've been leading you both for years.
我都带你们俩多少年了
What are you two up to together
你们俩一密谋什么
won't be hided from me.
我一眼我就看穿了
Just like
就像你们一眼
you can figure out my intention.
能看穿我一样
No.
不是
It's normal for you to know what we're up to.
你看穿我们很正常
But it matters
但是能够正确地
for a worker to understand
领会领导意图
the leader's intention
也是职场重要的
in the workplace.
生存法则
Everybody does it.
大家都这样的
Right.
是
To make you rest assured,
是为了给您宽心
I invited you to attend the meeting.
才让您来的
You know,
我这想着
I'm pregnant.
我这不是怀孕了吗
But I'm still competent for the job.
但是工作我还是能做的
After all, I've got the wisdom and experience needed.
毕竟脑子和经验还在嘛
I wish you won't worry about it.
不想让您太担心
Meng'an,
梦安
I'd like to be frank
那我也跟你
with you.
说一句心里话
I can understand
从个人情感角度上
and feel happy
来看吧
that you're pregnant
你怀二胎
with a
我真的是
second child.
打心里往外地高兴
It's a happy event
这孩子能
for you to give a safe and smooth birth
平安顺利地生下来
of the baby.
这是多大的喜事啊
But
可是从老板的
as a boss,
角度上来讲
I've to say
你这产假
your six-month maternity leave
一休息
is a long period.
就得休息六个月呀
We make content for growth.
我们是靠内容出身的
A new media company
新媒体公司
can't afford it.
承受不了这个呀
I'm getting anxious
我现在一想
at the thought of your leave
你要休息六个月 我
for six months.
我这心里真发慌啊
I know.
我知道
And I can understand it.
也特别能理解
So,
所以也就
let me put it this way.
这么说吧
As long as I can work here,
只要我还能上一天班
I'm gonna fight till the end of the day.
我肯定会拼到最后一天
During my maternity leave,
休产假这段时间
I'll definitely
我肯定也会提前
make the project, the team
把项目啊 人员啊
and the work all set.
工作都安排好
I won't promise the performance will be great.
不敢说业绩怎么样吧
But I'll make sure
但是不让新苗掉队
not to let the department fall behind.
我觉得我还是能做到的
Alright.
行
I feel a lot more secure
有你这句话
as you say it.
我心里也踏实多了
Then if I'll do something
那接下来
to make you
我要是做了一些
feel upset next,
让你不高兴的事
don't take it personally, either.
你也别往心里去啊
I won't.
不会
If I get emotional,
我要是有情绪了
it must be due to high progesterone.
肯定就是孕激素高了
Please understand it.
你也多担待点
You know,
不是
don't make me sit in on the internal meeting
你们这个内部开会
of your department again.
以后别让我过来旁听啊
I could have used the time to develop
有这时间
two more projects.
我还多拉两个项目
Rachel gave me a stupid idea this time.
这回她是真狗头了
Now the whole family
现在全家人
are way joyful
都因为我妈怀孕
for my mom's pregnancy.
喜笑颜开的
They always wear big smiles
嘴角都咧到后脑勺去了
that I can't bear with it.
就差敲锣打鼓了
My aunt came from our hometown
我大姑专门从老家过来
to take care of my mom.
照顾我妈
She made the braised fish,
做那红烧鱼
yet I'm not allowed
都不允许
to eat more.
我多吃两筷子的
She said it was for my mom.
说是要留给我妈
No need to be mad.
算了算了
Don't go back home for dinner tonight.
晚上别回家吃饭了
I'll buy you some grilled fish.
我请你吃烤鱼去
I didn't say it
我也不是为了
for that dish.
争那口鱼吃
I get it.
我知道
You're not mad at the dish.
你不是为了争口鱼
You just feel upset.
你就为了争那口气
I support you.
我支持你
Yes.
对
My status in the family
我现在的家庭地位
was won by myself.
就是我自己抗争得来的
How did you do it?
怎么抗争啊
I'll tell you.
我告诉你啊
Remind them
你要多在他们面前
frequently.
提点着点
They can't only care the second child and ignore the first one.
不能只管老二不管老大
They've to care
凡事要以老大的
the first child,
利益为先
then
先有老大的
the second one.
再有老二的
They've to
像什么一碗水端平啊
be fair at home.
在家也要公平 公正
Just say these words
这种词
in front of them more often.
就多在他们面前说一说
Is this workable?
你这靠谱吗
They're adults,
他们都多大的人了
smarter than us.
可比咱们精明
Well, it depends on the time you say.
这就要看你怎么说了
You've to say it
你要是没事就说
at the right time.
那肯定不行呀
Listen.
来
Here is a trick.
我教给你一个诀窍啊
For example,
就比如说
my parents may tell me off.
什么时候我爸妈训我了
He Lu,
何璐
why didn't you do the exam well?
你这次为什么没考好
Then I'll say
然后我就会说
you all care so much
你们平时只顾着
on my brother.
管阿瑞了
You've not paid attention
什么时候管过我的
to my study at all.
日常成绩呀
Now you're
现在又问我
asking me why?
为什么没考好
You can be an actress.
你要不去当演员吧
These are my tricks.
这都是我的绝技
If you
以后啊
don't do well next time,
你要是也没考好的话
tell your mom and dad that.
就这么跟爸妈说
Yunjie,
云阶
Ms. Xue asked you
薛老师找你
to go to the office.
让你去趟办公室
Let's go.
走吧
Why does Ms. Xue need to meet her?
薛老师找她干吗啊
Didn't she do well in the exam?
难道真的没考好
You failed either, didn't you?
你不也没考好吗
You're even at the bottom of the score.
你还垫底呢
Mind your own business.
管好你自己吧
Yunjie,
云阶啊
you scores are poor this time.
你这次摸底没有考好啊
I don't think
我发现你
you've focused
最近的这个心思啊
on your studies lately.
好像没有放在学习上
You failed in the exam twice in a row.
这连着两次失利了
You were still among top students
上个学期学新知识
for studying new knowledge during last semester.
你还是我们的尖子学生
Why did you
这怎么
lag behind
一到了整体复习阶段
in the review stage?
这成绩还往下掉了呢
How disappointed your parents will be?
你父母该多失望啊
As a Chinese teacher,
作为语文老师
I favor you a lot.
我是很喜欢你的
You have
你身上有
better literary quality.
很好的文艺修养
I don't require you to be a top student,
我不求你名列前茅
But you shouldn't
但是你也不要
fall too far behind.
这样子落后太多呀
I'll rearrange seats of the class.
我这次调整座位
Don't sit
你就不要跟那个何璐
with He Lu.
再坐在一起了
I'll arrange you as Zhu Kexin's deskmate.
我让你跟朱可欣同桌
She's got good grades.
她成绩不错
Hope you can learn from the good student
我希望你近朱者赤
and improve your grades as soon as possible.
尽快地把成绩提上来
Do you understand?
你明白吗
Yes.
我明白
Thank you, Ms. Xue.
谢谢薛老师
I'll be talking
回头我也会找你妈妈
to your mom about your performance, too.
好好聊聊的
Don't!
别
Ms. Xue,
薛老师
my mom's been occupied lately.
我妈她最近挺忙的
Does she have something
这还有什么
more important
比自己孩子的事
than your study?
更重要啊
Our family
我们家
is gonna have
马上就要有
another child soon.
另外一个孩子了
Come in.
进
Mr. Qian.
钱总
I just received
我刚刚收到了
the salary information of this month.
这个月的工资信息
But only half of my commission
我的销售提成
is paid, why?
怎么只有百分之五十啊
Well,
你这样啊
you go to the finance account department
你去公司理财账户
to open an account.
开个户
The wealth management products
按相应额度
of the amount will be transferred to you.
把理财产品的转给你
I don't want the products.
我不要理财产品
I need cash.
我需要现金
All employees of our company
咱们公司的员工
have a financial account.
都要有理财账户
And it has revenues.
而且有收益
Much higher than the yield of depositing them in the bank.
比你存银行高多了
If there're written rules,
那有没有成文的规定
please show me.
您给我看一下
You're my subordinate.
你在我手下干
You've to play by my rules.
就得按我规矩来
If you want it, okay.
你要要你就要
If not, that's your loss.
不要啊 那就算了
If so,
如果这样的话
may I
我是不是可以
complain to
向公司总部
the head office
或者劳动仲裁部门
or labor arbitration department?
申诉呢
Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真
don't you want the job?
你是不不想干了
Mr. Qian, to be honest.
钱总 说实话
I'm worried
我是担心公司
as so many wealth management products are released.
增发这么多理财产品
In case there's a run on a bank,
到时候一旦发生挤兑
what should we do?
你该怎么办
Our company is large,
我们公司家大业大的
and with so many real estate projects.
而且有这么多地产项目
We don't need
用不着你这半瓶醋
you to give your advice here.
在这儿指手画脚
You're in the management.
您是高层 您一定知道
I bet you know it's not that profitable
这卖房子
to sell real estates.
没有那么高的利润的
I know you studied finance.
你是学金融的
If you wanna work here, it's okay.
你要想干你就干
If not, you can quit.
不想干你就走人
Don't mess around here.
你别在这儿瞎搅和
Moreover,
而且
don't say openly
你刚才那句话
about what you just mentioned.
如果敢出去乱说的话
Or, I'll fire you at any time.
我分分钟把你开了
Believe it or not?
你信不信
You can fire me.
你可以开了我
But I need
但是我也要拿到
to get my commission.
我应得的那一部分提成
If I can't get it,
如果拿不到
I'll stay
我就留在这儿
and see
我倒要看看
if the revenue of wealth management products
理财产品的收益
is that promising
是不是像您说的那样
like you said.
形势一片大好
The score is not good.
这成绩是不太行啊
She...
她这是
She didn't do well this time.
她这是没考好啊
We caught up with the teaching schedule
上个学期啊
last semester.
我们赶教学进度
The lessons were taught much in a short time.
学得很快
Many students fell behind on their studies.
很多学生都掉队
But Yunjie did well
但那个时候云阶的成绩
at that time.
是不错的
She was even
属于我们班
among the top 20 percent of students in the class.
前百分之二十的学生
But lately
但最近啊
we were in the overall review phase.
进入到整体复习阶段
She wasn't doing well
她这连着两次摸底
twice in a row.
成绩都不太理想
Was something
我想问一下
going on at home?
是家里有什么事吗
Her grandpa got sick some time ago.
前段时间她外公生病了
And her aunt had a premature labor.
然后她小姨又早产
The family was in chaos.
家里头兵荒马乱的
I guess her dad cared less about her.
估计她爸可能没太顾上
It maybe won't last long.
那应该过段时间就好了
This knowledge
这旧的知识啊
should be reviewed more.
还是要多巩固 多复习
Yes.
是 是
One more thing I wanna ask.
我还想问一件事啊
Yunjie said
就是我听云阶说
you were pregnant.
您怀二胎啦
Yes.
是
I've just got pregnant for a short time.
也刚怀
I was doing fetus protection a couple of days ago.
前两天还保胎呢
She might be
云阶可能也受
affected by this.
这个事影响了
I can understand it.
特别能理解
I've been a head teacher for long.
我当班主任这么久了
Now
现在啊
the birth policy is relaxed.
生育政策放开了
More and more families
像你们家这样的情况
are in the same situation like yours.
越来越多了
Many parents
很多家长
choose to have another child.
都选择再要一个孩子
It's your choice.
这是你们自己的选择
But it's a key period
但是呢
of the high school entrance examination for Yunjie.
老大在中考的关键时期
Please pay more attention to her, too.
也要给予更多的关注
The baby is still
这毕竟二胎
unborn after all.
不是还在肚子里吗
Exactly.
是
Not born.
在肚子里呢
When students play games,
我就听学生嘛
it goes around
他们之间流传着
among them
这个玩游戏的
a joke.
一个玩笑话
It tells us something.
但是也很能说明问题
It goes "the first child is the main account
就说 老大是大号
while the second one is an alt account.
二胎呢 是小号
Even the parents are busy
这家长忙着练小号
with the second,
也不能把
the first child cannot be neglected."
大号给荒废了吧
No.
不荒废
Honey,
老婆
coming back for dinner?
晚上回来吃饭吗
How about I ask my sister to cook some meat dishes?
我让姐再添几个肉菜啊
You've even got time to think about the dishes?
还有心情吃肉菜呢
Have you checked messages in the parent WeChat group?
家长群里的消息看了吗
WeChat group?
群
What did they say?
群里面说什么
I knew you hadn't watched it.
就知道你没看
Wang Zhe's mom said
王哲妈妈
there was a lecture
说有个讲座
about mathematical logical thinking.
数学逻辑思维的
I know it.
那个事我知道
I'm planning
这不是正打算晚上回去
to talk to you about it.
跟你商量吗
No need to talk to me about it, okay?
这事还用跟我商量吗
You're responsible
云阶的学习
for Yunjie's study, aren't you?
不都是你抓的吗
You know
你知道我现在
where I am?
在哪儿呢吗
I'm at school.
我在学校
I was called by the teacher to the school again.
我又被老师叫来学校了
The teacher asked you to go again.
老师又叫你去学校了
Why does she call you to go there a lot?
她怎么老叫你呢
You know what?
这说明什么呀
It means you're not doing a good job.
说明你管得不够好
You're talking to me
你不是要跟我商量
about the lecture?
讲座的事吗
Tell me. What's your decision?
说吧 给个态度
What's your plan?
怎么着
Calm down.
消消气
Don't be angry.
别生气
So,
这样
let's sign up.
那咱们就报呗
Okay?
是吧
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
那行 这事就交给你了
If you can't talk Yunjie in,
你要是搞不定你闺女
just wait and see what will happen tonight.
看我晚上不作死你
What's wrong?
怎么了
Why was she so upset?
这这 火气这么大
Hello, Wang Zhe's mom?
王哲妈妈